Guide to the Marvin and Theresa (Terry) Miller Papers WAG.165
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
- Series II: Major League Baseball Players Association, 1949-2005
  - National Football League Players Association, 1972-1976 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - National Football League: MM Times Article, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - National Hockey League, 1966-1992-1992 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - National Hockey League Players Association: Eagleson Case, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Negotiations, undated, 1966-1969 (Box 4, Folder 18-20)
  - Negotiations (Clippings), 1968-1969 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Negotiations, 1970-1976 (Box 4, Folder 22-26)
  - Negotiations (Clippings), 1976 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Negotiations, 1977-1981 (Box 4, Folder 28-30)
  - Negotiations, 1980-1981 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Negotiations (Clippings), 1980-1981 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Negotiations, 1982-1995 (Box 5, Folder 3-7)
  - Negotiations: Draft Articles, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Nixon, President Richard M., 1969-1988 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Noll, Roger G., "Baseball Economics in the 1990s", 1994 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Oral History Interview: American Jewish Committee Project, 1991-1993 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Oral History Interviews: H. Golatz, Pennsylvania State University, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Oral History Interview: Nicholas Mauro, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Orange County Business Journal: The Business of Baseball (Special Issue), 1990 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Organized Labor: General, 1974-1985-1985 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Owners: General, 1973-1986-1986 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Player Representatives, 1970-1978-1978 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Player Selection: Compensation Issue, 1978-1981-1981 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Players' Biographies: Misc., 1953, 1967-1979 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Playoffs/ World Series Pool, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Public Sports Policy, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Re-entry Draft, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Reserve Clause, 1969-1976 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Revenue Sharing: MM Column, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Rona, Barry: Arbitration Case, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Rose, Pete, 1987-1991 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Rose, Pete (Clippings), 1967, 1983-1992 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Rose, Pete vs. A. Bartlett Giamatti et al., 1989 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Salaries, 1966-1988 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Salary (MM), 1970-1972 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Salary Data, 1956, 1976-1981 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Santo, Ron, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Schedules: Spring Training, 1967-1987 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Seitz, Peter, 1974-1983 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Shalit, Gene, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Shore, Bradd, "Loading the Bases", 1990 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Shukan Besuboru [Baseball Weekly], Japan: Miller Articles, July 1992-April 1993 (Box 5, Folder 37-39)
  - Silverman vs. MLBPA and Member Clubs of Major League Baseball: Briefs, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Sixty-Forty Case: Arbitration, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Smith, Red, undated, 1967-1982 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Speeches: Texts and Notes, undated, 1967-1977 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Sporting News: Marvin Miller Letter, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Sports Union: Proposal, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Spring Training Notes, etc., 1979-1982 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Steinbrenner/Spira Case: Commissioner's Ruling, etc., 1990 (Box 6, Folder 7-8)
  - Strike (Clippings), 1972 (Box 6, Folder 9-13)
  - Strike (Clippings), 1981 (Box 6, Folder 14-16)
  - Strike: Correspondence, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 17-18)
  - Strike: Hank Margolis Paper on 1981, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Strike: Radio-TV Clips, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Strike: Aftermath, 1981-1982 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Strike (Clippings), 1985 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Strike (Clippings), 1994 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Testimony (Marvin Miller): Unidentified, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Testimony (Marvin Miller): Unidentified Grievance Procedure, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Tolan Case, 1974-1978 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Topps Case, May 1993 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Topps Case: Transcripts, May 1993 (Box 7, Folder 6-10)
  - Topps Case: Transcripts, June 1993 (Box 7, Folder 11-14)
  - Topps Case: Transcripts, June 1993 (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
  - Ueberroth, Peter, 1984-1989 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Umpires, 1968-1990 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - U.S. Congress: Committee on the Judiciary, Marvin Miller Testimony, 1972, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - U.S. Congress: Committee on the Judiciary, Selig Statement, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - U.S. Congress: Select Committee on Professional Sports, Miller Statements, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Veeck, Bill, 1972-1976 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Vincent, Fay, 1989-1992 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Vincent, Fay: Firing, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Vincent, Fay: Steven Howe Dispute, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Wald, Malvin, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Weaver, Earl, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Whole Different Ball Game, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Williams, Ted, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Winfield, Dave: Tampering Case, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Writings (MM): Miscellaneous, undated (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Wynegar, Harold D. "Butch", Jr., 1986 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Yastrzemski, Carl, 1969-1970 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Young, Dick, undated, 1966-1987 (Box 8, Folder 20)
- Series III: Clippings Files, 1966-2002
  Series III: Clippings Files, 1966-2002, arranged chronologically, by year. This series, containing thousands of clippings from a wide range of national and local newspapers, as well as sports-related and general magazines, parallels Series II in its coverage of issues and events central to MLBPA history, of baseball matters in general, and of developments in the world of sports and in national news that had an impact on labor relations in baseball.
  - Clippings, undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Clippings, 1966-1968 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Clippings, 1969-1971 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Clippings, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Clippings, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Clippings, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Clippings, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 7-8)
  - Clippings, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Clippings, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Clippings, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Clippings, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 12-15)
  - Clippings, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 16-19)
  - Clippings, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Clippings, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Clippings, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Clippings, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Clippings, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Clippings, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Clippings, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Clippings, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Clippings, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Clippings, 1991-1992 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Clippings, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Clippings, 1995 (Box 10, Folder 7-8)
  - Clippings, 2001 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Clippings, January 2002 (Box 10, Folder 10-14)
- Series IV: Videotapes (VHS), 1987-2009
  Series IV: Videotapes (VHS), 1987-2002, arranged chronologically. Contents include news clips, interviews and speeches by Marvin Miller, in which he discusses current baseball developments, his career with the MLBPA, and labor history from a broad perspective, touching on topics as diverse as the New Deal, the Taft-Hartley Act, the Baseball Hall of Fame, and the careers of Joe DiMaggio, Pete Rose and Walter O'Malley. Also included is a PBS broadcast in which Charlie Rose interviews Bob Costas, author of Fair Ball, a study of the economics of baseball.
  - "Today" with Bryant Gumbel, June 1991 (Box 10)
  - Later...with Bob Costas: Interview with Marvin Miller, October 14, 1991 (Box 10)
  - Marvin Miller Interview for Fay Vincent, September 1, 1992 (Box 10)
  - Marvin Miller: Nation Forum, May 1, 1995 (Box 10)
  - Marvin Miller Interviewed by Del Reddy, November 1997 (Box 10)
  - ESPN's Sports Century, May 23, 1999 (Box 10)
  - Fran Healey: MSG-TV, 2000 (Box 10)
  - Budd Mishkin (Ch. 1) Interview with Marvin Miller; Charlie Rose (Ch. 13) Interview with Bob Costas; Tim McCarver (MSG-TV) and MM, April 2000 (Box 10)
  - New York Jewish Sports Hall of Fame Presents Jewish Sports Legends of the 20th Century, April 2, 2000 (Box 10)
  - Al Trautwig with Marvin Miller: Baseball Labor Relations, April 22, 2002 (Box 10)
  - Sports Illustrated Party "40 for the Ages" [NBC-Night After the S.I. Party], Sep 14, 1994 (Box 14)
  - Newsport Talk Sports News [Port Washington NY 516.621.9451/Michele Elgart], Apr 13, 1995 (Box 14)
  - Frank Healy- MJM Interview [Hotel Warwick], Aug 1994 (Box 14)
  - ESPN Sports Century, "Most Influential 10" [Taped from TV], May 23, 1999 (Box 14)
  - Baseball Reliquary-Induction Day 2003 [B-Roll Tape 3-1hr.-Raw Footage Copy], Jul 21, 2003 (Box 14)
  - Marvin J. Miller- Barbara Walters, 20/20; Al Trautwig, Ch. 10: Steinbrenner [Marker 1222-1638], Aug 1990 (Box 14)
  - Reliquary "Shrine of the Eternals"- Induction Day [from Terry Cannon - "very bad VHS copy, but sound should be fine-for transcription purposes only] Raw Footage - Camera A, Jul 2003 (Box 14)
  - Charlie Rose Show - Fay Vincent Resignation [from marker 630-830] [now reset at 0 to 200], Sep 8, 1992 (Box 14)
  - ESPN Sports Classic - Sports Century: Ball Four (Documentary) Hans Decher, 2002 (Box 14)
  - Budd Mishkin with Marvin Miller, Feb 9, 2009 (Box 14)
  - Today Show with Bryant Gumbel, undated (Box 14)
  - Cornel Industrial Labor Relations Dept. (IRL) Interns- Marvin Miller, Mar 27, 1995 (Box 14)
  - Jim Kaat's Telecast - Birthday Greeting to Marvin J. Miller, Apr 14,1999 (Box 14)
  - Inside Baseball with Marvin Miller, undated (Box 14)
  - Talking Baseball with Marvin Miller (Parts 1 & 2), Jan 20, 1995 (Box 14)
  - Today Show [marker 2370-2550] - Bill Mazur [marker 2600], Jan 14, 1990 (Box 14)
  - Howard Cosell with Marvin Miller, 1985 (Box 14)
  - NYU/Tamiment Library - Evening of Celebration in Honor of Marvin Miller Archive (Donation of Papers, Artifacts), May 21, 2003 (Box 14)
  - World Series - Tim McCarver, 2009 (Box 14)
  - HBO - Sports Illustrated TV - Marvin Miller Initerview, Pt. 1 ["Dub of OT-30-4347"], Jul 25, 1994 (Box 14)
  - Dick Schapp - Interview with Marvin Miller [Held in White Plains/Eric Neulard(?)], undated (Box 14)
  - CNN Financial News [FN] Money and Markets [Marvin Miller'sApperarance], Aug 22, 2002 (Box 14)
  - Newsport Talk- Marvin Miller, Founder- MLBPA [TRT: 23:16], Feb 9, 1995 (Box 14)
  - Peggy Browining Fund (Chicago), May 6, 2003 (Box 14)
  - Trans World Int'l- Trans World Sport [Michael Maynard/London] [Job No. 20116] VHS NTSC/Prog. 546 (Dur: 52'12"), Oct 15, 1997 (Box 14)
  - Jack Cafferty, ch 5- with Marvin Miller... (Murray Chass), Jul 31, 1990 (Box 14)
  - "Angles"- MSG/AL Trautwig; Talking Baseball/Ed Randall, Apr 22, 2002; May 02, 2002 (Box 14)
  - CNBC- with Marvin Miller [Chris Shearn- Fort Lee, NJ/Assoc. Prod., Sports], circa 1997 (Box 14)
  - Harry Bridges: A Man and his Union [Hamilton, undated (Box 14)
  - Inside Sports- Show #438. Toronoto, Canada. Filmed at 211 E. 70th St., Summer 1994 (Box 15)
  - NY Channel 1- Budd Mishkin (to marker 509); NBC Sports Illustrated: "40 for the Ages" (to maker 990); Adam Smith (to marker 1337)., Aug 18, 1994 (Box 15)
  - Baseball Unions National Politics [Del Reddy 1.800.497.1035], Nov 1997 (Box 15)
  - Marvin Miller: Interview Fay Vincent [time 31:42], Sep 1, 1992 (Box 15)
  - CNBC: Sports Business, Feb 28, 1990 (Box 15)
  - Budd Mishkin - Channel 1 [to 38 min]; Charlie Rose - Chanel 13 [38 min to 1 hr 14 min]; Tim McCarver - MSG - ch. 27 [from 1 hr 14 min], undated (Box 15)
  - Talking Baseball, Show #521 with Ed Randall, May 2, 2002 (Box 15)
  - Angles with Marvin J. Miller - MSG Network [Al Trautwig], Apr 22, 2002 (Box 15)
  - The NY Jewish Sports hall of Fame: Jewish Sports Legends of the 20th Century, Apr 2, 2000 (Box 15)
  - Sports Illustrated Party, Jul 13, 1994 (Box 15)
  - Up Close Show #615-691 [Roy Firestone], June 1991 (Box 15)
  - At the Plate: Rusty Staub [commissioners, small markets, Vincent resignation], 1993 (Box 15)
  - Peptalk [Simmons] Long Beach, CA, Jun 25, 1991 (Box 15)
  - Today Show (marker 79: Lead-in; 131-244: Today Show; 249-356: Dick Schaap; 379-530: Rock Rote; 540-924: Pete Rose/Jane Pauley;; 1008-1220: Ed Randall), undated (Box 15)
  - Arthur Ashe, undated (Box 15)
  - Real Sports, Show #5, 1998 (Box 15)
  - ESPN Classic: One on One [Dick Schaap][Jim Brown], undated (Box 15)
  - ESPN's Sports Century [Curt Flood], undated (Box 15)
  - Football Strike [Mike Lupica/Marvin J. Miller] (11.5 to 19 mins?); The Coors Sports Page (30 min), Oct 11, 1987 (Box 15)
  - Jack Cafferty, Ch. 5 (marker 000-2000), July 31 (Box 15)
  - The Business of Sports, Season 1, Episode 7; Insight Sports Ltd. (Toronto, ONT), Apr 1, 2001 (Box 15)
  - CNN/Sports Illustrated [This Week in the NBA with Marvin J. Miller], Nov, 1, 1998 (Box 15)
  - National Jewish Sports Hall of Fame [Marvin J. Miller Induction Ceremony], Apr 26, 2009 (Box 15)
  - HBO: Marvin Miller Interview [S.I. TV], Jul 25, 1994 (Box 15)
  - Later...with Bob Costas (22 mins), Oct 14, 1991 (Box 15)
  - The Shrine of the Eternals [Induction Day-BB Reliquary] (Jim Bouton/Satchel Paige), Jul 29, 2001 (Box 15)
  - CNN: Marvin J. Miller [Talk Back Live], Aug 12, 1997 (Box 15)
  - C-Span [John Feinstein] The New Millennium Baseball and Marvin Miller [30 mins.], Jan 2000 (Box 15)
  - TSN Series: For the Love of the Game - Behind the Screen (50 min) [Program #3] Producer: Alan Scherberger., undated (Box 15)
  - MSG - Fran Healey (27.5 mins), Apr 2000 (Box 15)
  - Sports Behind Bars - For the Love of the Game (52 mins), undated (Box 15)
  - ESPN Classics: Curt Flood (Richard Widman), undated (Box 15)
- Series V: Theresa (Terry) Miller Papers, 1919-1994
  Series V: Theresa M. Miller Files, 1919-1994, arranged alphabetically by topic. This series consists of personal and professional files of his wife, Theresa Morgenstern Miller. Included are her 1961 University of Pittsburgh Ph.D. thesis, several of her professional papers in the field of psychology, and articles she wrote for Union Reporter and Southern Jewish Outlook, among other publications. There are also voters' guides and petitions related to Theresa Miller's 1948 run for New York State Assembly on the American Labor Party ticket.
  - Academic Files and Awards, 1955-1989, undated (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Birth Certificate, 1919 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Brooklyn College Class of 1938 Fiftieth Reunion, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, Personal, 1954-1989 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, Professional, 1955-1980 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - "Dyadic Serendipity" (unpublished?), undated (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Political Activities: American Labor Party Assembly Campaign, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Thesis "Intelligence and Laboratory Learning: Two Dimensions of Laboratory Tasks" (Ph.D., University of Pittsburgh, 1961) (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Writings, 1946-1994, undated (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Scrapbooks (Box 11)